Guide to the Pauline Kolenda papers, 1950-1999.
Kolenda, Pauline papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Pauline Kolenda papers, 1950-1999.
8456
Kolenda, Pauline.
40 cubic feet.
Digital Media, Correspondence, Printed Material, Research Material
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection consists of field notes and research files.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Pauline Kolenda was an anthropologist who studied India.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection consists of field notes and research files.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kolenda, Pauline.
Subjects:
Families -- India.; Caste -- India; Villages -- India.
Places:
India -- Civilization
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Kanyakumari Study
Series II. Khalapur materials
Series III. Miscellaneous
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I: Kanyakumari Study
  - Genealogies with lists and notebooks (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous and Problems, maps (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous papers (Box 2, 3)
  - Sorted genealogies without lists (Box 3, 4)
  - Family charts and notebooks (Box 4, 5)
  - Field notes and files related to Tamilnadu (Box 5, 6)
  - Field notes, photographs, and miscellaneous files (Box 6, 7)
  - Miscellaneous, graduate students from University of Houston (Box 7)
- Series II: Khalapur materials
  - Rankhandi, including maternal health notes (Box 9, 10)
  - Miscellaneous material, including RA notes from the 1980s (Box 10, 11)
  - Miscellaneous, RA notes, 1984 (Box 11, 12)
  - Khandan Study (Box 12, 13)
  - Field notes, including trips to India (Box 13, 14)
  - Field Notes (Box 14, 15)
  - Notes, with some from Rajput 1983 (Box 35, 36)
  - Daily activity notes (Box 39, 40)
  - Miscellaneous material (Box 40, 41, 42)
  - Miscellaneous, 1954, 1984 (Box 42, 43)
  - Miscellaneous papers, correspondence (Box 43, 44)
- Series III: Miscellaneous
  - "Village Study" (Box 8, 9)
  - Notes from Helena Kolenda, 1984 (Box 15, 16)
  - Fields notes from Champapura (Box 16, 17)
  - Champapura census records, floppy disks (Box 17, 18)
  - Demography lectures, UC Berkeley, 1982 (Box 18, 19)
  - Brahman files (Box 19, 20, 21, 22)
  - Miscellaneous files, Nadars, floppy Disks (Box 22, 23)
  - Miscellaneous Cornell papers (Box 23, 24)
  - Papers, Conferences, Book Reviews (Box 25, 26)
  - First write up of Jaipur study for Cornell. Thesis - Dimensions of Personality as Related to Dimensions of Prejudice in a Survey of a Northeastern City, 1955 (Box 26, 27)
  - Materials from The Tamil Family Life and Values Project of the University of Houston, 1971 (Box 28, 29)
  - Book Reviews and Reprints (Box 27, 28)
  - Notes from Rankhandi, miscellaneous papers (Box 29, 30, 31)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 31, 32)
  - Grant Proposals, Super Computer San Diego, Miscellaneous, audio visual material (Box 32, 33)
  - Jajmani material, miscellaneous files, Rankhandi project records, audio visual material (Box 34, 35)
  - Miscellaneous files and book reviews, Paradox computer manual, audio visual material (Box 35, 37)
  - Miscellaneous, some from Khalapur (Box 37, 38)
  - Field notes, ca. 1983 (Box 38, 39)
  - Various papers, including work on dowry paper; material external review of U Virginia Asian studies department (Box 44, 45)
  - Personal materials, including passport and cover letter, college at Wellesley, articles and photos (Box 45, 46)
  - Manuals on Paradox, floppy discs with India papers (Box 47)
  - Professional and personal correspondence, including Mike Mahar, Konstantin Kolenda, William Rowe. (Box 46, 47)
  - Slides of India, some in binder (Box 47)
  - Timeline drawings, Tube 1
  - India outline maps used for JT family project, 1980s; Tube 1